Frank L. Smith Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frank L. Smith collection
1911-1936
1911-1919
YCAL MSS 1123
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5.75
4 boxes
Collection consists of correspondence, typescripts, photographs, performance programs and other ephemera primarily relating to Frank L. Smith's career as a theatrical press and advance agent for burlesque shows produced by Max Spiegel on the burlesque theater circuit from circa 1916 to 1919. Correspondence chiefly consists of Smith's communications with theaters in which the shows were to perform, and with Max Spiegel regarding issues concerning the productions. Typescripts include press releases and articles by Smith publicizing performers and productions including George Armstrong, Florence Mills, Abe Reynolds, the Watson Sisters and the Merry Rounders. Photographs include portrait and candid photographs of Smith, Spiegel, and unidentified male and female performers. The collection also includes Spiegel production playbills and programs and publicity materials; mock-ups of posters and original pen and ink caricatures of Smith; a small group of personal papers; and a scrapbook containing newspaper clippings relating to Smith's work on the burlesque theater circuit.
Smith, Frank L., 1882-1953
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Frank L. Smith (1882-1953)
Frank L. Smith was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1882. As a boy Smith worked in various capacities for travelling circuses and other entertainments. After meeting John M. "Major" Burke (renowned for his general management of William Cody's Wild West Show), Smith worked under Burke's tutelage in his company's press department. In the mid 1900's Smith joined Max Spiegel's New York City-based burlesque production company as a press and advance agent, travelling the burlesque theater circuit from the East Coast to the Midwest. He later managed theaters for Lee and J. J. Shubert in Newark, New Jersey, and New York City. Smith served on the board of governors of the Association of the Theatrical Press Agents and Managers Union from its establishment in 1928, and as president from 1949 until his death in 1953. He was married to Mildred Tyson, a former performer in one of the Spiegel productions.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of correspondence, typescripts, photographs, performance programs and other ephemera primarily relating to Frank L. Smith's career as a theatrical press and advance agent for burlesque shows produced by Max Spiegel on the burlesque theater circuit from circa 1916 to 1919. Correspondence chiefly consists of Smith's communications with theaters in which the shows were to perform, and with Max Spiegel regarding issues concerning the productions. Typescripts include press releases and articles by Smith publicizing performers and productions including George Armstrong, Florence Mills, Abe Reynolds, the Watson Sisters and the Merry Rounders. Photographs include portrait and candid photographs of Smith, Spiegel, and unidentified male and female performers. The collection also includes Spiegel production playbills and programs and publicity materials; mock-ups of posters and pen and ink caricatures of Smith; a small group of personal papers; and a scrapbook containing newspaper clippings relating to Smith's work on the burlesque theater circuit.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of material.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Reese Co. on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2012.
Actors -- United States; Burlesque (Theater) -- United States; Press agents -- United States; Theatrical managers -- United States; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States; Drawings (visual works); Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Actors -- United States; Press agents -- United States; Theatrical managers -- United States; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States; Armstrong, George, active 1916; Mills, Florence; Reynolds, Abe; Smith, Frank L., 1882-1953; Spiegel, Max
- Correspondence, 1911-1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  Scope and Contents
  Chiefly related to Smith's work as press and advance agent for Max Spiegel productions
- Typescript publicity articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
  Includes articles and press releases on performers and productions, and the history of burlesque; most untitled
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  Includes photographs of Smith, Spiegel, and unidentified male and female performers
- Group photograph of actors and actresses, undated (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 32)
  Includes John Drew and William Cody
- Production programs and flyers, 1913-1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Chiefly programs and flyers for Max Spiegel burlesque touring productions
- Advertisement flongs, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Two flongs for Max Spiegel's Abe Reynolds' Revue
- Theater-related ephemera, 1913-1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  Includes brochures, advertisements, menus, etc.
- Personal papers, 1913-1929, undated (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  Includes bank books, business card, New Jersey vehicle registration, certificate of incorporation of Civic Light Opera Company, Newark, New Jersey (undated); and material relating to his grand jury service in Newark, New Jersey
- Souvenir performance programs, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Includes Tobacco Road and Cyrano de Bergerac starring Walter Hampden
- Captain Billy's Whiz Bang, 1921 August (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Issue of "America's Magazine of Wit, Humor and Filosphy" published by W. H. Fawcett, Robbinsdale, Minnesota
- Scrapbook, 1916-1919, undated (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 19)
  Includes clippings regarding Smith, Spiegel, and their burlesque productions and stars Florence Mills and Abe Reynolds; clippings pasted into blank electors' enrollment list ledger for Rochester, New York
- Loose clippings from scrapbook, 1916-1933, undated (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 20-22)
- Playbills from scrapbook, 1910-1919, undated (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 23)
- Caricatures of Frank Smith, undated (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 24-29)
  Includes original posters advertising annual parties hosted by Smith
- Caricatures of Frank Smith, undated (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 33-36)
- Mock-up of poster for Abe Renolds' Revue, undated (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 30)
- Mock-up of poster for Merry Rounders, undated (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 31)
- Drawing of Evelyn Herbert, undated (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 37)